Guide to the Eugene L. Armbruster Photograph Collection 1894-1939 PR 81
New-York Historical Society
- Series II: Negatives
  - Subseries I, Acetate Film Negatives: 4 x 5"
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Flatlands (355), undated (Offsite-box 11, Box 11)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Gravesend (207), undated (Offsite-box 11, Box 11)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--New Lots (73), undated (Offsite-box 11, Box 11)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--New Utrecht (77), undated (Offsite-box 11, Box 11)
    - New York--Lake Mohegan (50), undated (Offsite-box 12, Box 12)
    - New York--Long Island (mixed) (15), undated (Offsite-box 12, Box 12)
    - New York--Nassau County--Hempstead (32), undated (Offsite-box 12, Box 12)
    - New York--Nassau County--Oyster Bay (1), undated (Offsite-box 12, Box 12)
    - New York--New York County (Manhattan) (144), undated (Offsite-box 12, Box 12)
    - New York--Orange County--Newburgh (27), undated (Offsite-box 12, Box 12)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Brookhaven (347), undated (Offsite-box 12, Box 12)
    - New York--Suffolk County--East Hampton (107), undated (Offsite-box 12, Box 12)
    - New York--Suffolk County--East Hampton (204) (Offsite-box 13, Box 13)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Hamptons (86), undated (Offsite-box 13, Box 13)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Huntington (16), undated (Offsite-box 13, Box 13)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Islip (8), undated (Offsite-box 13, Box 13)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Montauk (452), undated (Offsite-box 13, Box 13)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Shelter Island (1) (Offsite-box 14, Box 14)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Southampton (341), undated (Offsite-box 14, Box 14)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Southold (21), undated (Offsite-box 14, Box 14)
    - New York--Richmond County (Staten Island) (16), undated (Offsite-box 14, Box 14)
    - New York--Queens County--Far Rockaway (38), undated (Offsite-box 14, Box 14)
    - New York--Queens County--Flushing (324), undated (Offsite-box 14, Box 14)
    - New York--Queens County--Flushing (129), undated (Offsite-box 15, Box 15)
    - New York--Queens County--Jamaica (407), undated (Offsite-box 15, Box 15)
    - New York--Queens County--Long Island City (245), undated (Offsite-box 15, Box 15)
    - New York--Queens County--Newtown (840), undated (Offsite-box 16, Box 16)
    - New York--Queens County--Newtown (423), undated (Offsite-box 17, Box 17)
    - New York--Queens County--Rockaway Peninsula (19), undated (Offsite-box 17, Box 17)
    - New York--Westchester County (75), undated (Offsite-box 17, Box 17)
    - Pennsylvania (102), undated (Offsite-box 17, Box 17)
    - Vermont (47), undated (Offsite-box 17, Box 17)
    - Vermont, New Hampshire (41), undated (Offsite-box 17, Box 17)
    - Vermont, New Hampshire, Massachusetts (60), undated (Offsite-box 17, Box 17)
    - Canada (287), undated (Offsite-box 18, Box 18)
    - Unidentified (340), undated (Offsite-box 18, Box 18)
    - Unidentified (448), undated (Offsite-box 19, Box 19)
    - Deteriorated negatives, undated (Offsite-box 19, Box 19)
  - Subseries II, Nitrate Film Negatives: 5 x 7"
    Subseries II is composed mainly of views of residential houses, including some of Brooklyn row houses. Most of these photographs appear to be on Long Island; many shots show wooden, farm-like houses. The same scene is often shown in several negatives. A churchyard in East Hampton is pictured with an elaborate sepulchre. Windmills are shown for many of the Long Island towns. Several of the negative boxes had Armbruster's notation on the geographical location of negative subjects. The negatives in the boxes which lacked any notation have been arranged by general subject category.
    Nitrate negatives were interleaved with acid free paper and stored five to a negative sleeve. Several of the negative boxes had Armbruster's notation on geographical place of negatives. These negatives are grouped by geography after Armbruster's titles (which appear in quotation marks) and then further divided by subject. Many other boxes had no notation. These negatives were arranged by general subject category. Nitrate negatives were assigned box numbers in coordination with other nitrate negatives held by the New-York Historical Society. These negatives are located on Floor 14 in the N-YHS Library Stacks. (See also, Separated Material)
    - "Amaganset, Wainscott "--Farms, undated (Box N26)
    - "Amaganset, Wainscott "--Houses, undated (Box N26)
    - "Amaganset, Wainscott "--Landscapes, undated (Box N26)
    - "Amaganset, Wainscott "--Windmills (Box N26)
    - "East Hampton"--Churches/churchyards, undated (Box N26)
    - "East Hampton"--Farms, undated (Box N26)
    - "East Hampton"--Houses, undated (Box N26)
    - "East Hampton"--Windmills, undated (Box N26)
    - "Gravesend, New Utrecht, New Lots, Canarsie", undated (Box N26)
    - "Huntington-Old House", undated (Box N26)
    - "Manhasset -- Roslyn, Little Neck, Dougleston, Alley Road"--Houses, undated (Box N26)
    - "Manhasset -- Roslyn, Little Neck, Dougleston, Alley Road"--Landscapes, undated (Box N26)
    - "Manhasset -- Roslyn, Little Neck, Dougleston, Alley Road"--Other, undated (Box N26)
    - "Melville Alley, Moriches"--Buildings, undated (Box N26)
    - "Melville Alley, Moriches"--Farmhouses, undated (Box N26)
    - "Melville Alley, Moriches"--Houses, undated (Box N27)
    - "Melville Alley, Moriches"--Landscapes, undated (Box N27)
    - "New York-Brooklyn"--Buildings, undated (Box N27)
    - "New York-Brooklyn"--Other, undated (Box N27)
    - "New York-Brooklyn"--Rowhouses, undated (Box N27)
    - "New York-Brooklyn"--Streets, undated (Box N27)
    - "New York-Skyline", undated (Box N27)
    - "Patchogue, Bell Port, Yaphank, Brookhaven, Middle Is., Selden, Corem"--Architectural elements, undated (Box N27)
    - "Patchogue, Bell Port, Yaphank, Brookhaven, Middle Is., Selden, Corem"--Houses, undated (Box N27)
    - "Patchogue, Bell Port, Yaphank, Brookhaven, Middle Is., Selden, Corem"--Landscapes, undated (Box N27)
    - "Patchogue, Bell Port, Yaphank, Brookhaven, Middle Is., Selden, Corem"--People, undated (Box N27)
    - "Ryerson"--Houses, undated (Box N27)
    - "Ryerson"--Interiors, undated (Box N27)
    - "Stony-Brook, South-Haven, Happauge"--Barns, undated (Box N27)
    - "Stony-Brook, South-Haven, Happauge"--Houses, undated (Box N28)
    - "Stony-Brook, South-Haven, Happauge"--Landscapes, undated (Box N28)
    - "Stony-Brook, South-Haven, Happauge"--Other, undated (Box N28)
    - Unidentified location---Architectural elements, undated (Box N28)
    - Unidentified location--Barns, undated (Box N28)
    - Unidentified location--Boats, undated (Box N28)
    - Unidentified location--Buildings, undated (Box N28)
    - Unidentified location--Cars, undated (Box N28)
    - Unidentified location--Churches, undated (Box N28)
    - Unidentified location--Dams, undated (Box N28)
    - Unidentified location--Farmhouses, undated (Box N28)
    - Unidentified location--Houses, undated (Box N28)
    - Unidentified location--Houses, undated (Box N29)
    - Unidentified location--Houses, undated (Box N30)
    - Unidentified location--Houses, undated (Box N31)
    - Unidentified location--Interiors, undated (Box N31)
    - Unidentified location--Landscapes, undated (Box N31)
    - Unidentified location--Other, undated (Box N31)
    - Unidentified location--People, undated (Box N31)
    - Unidentified location--Row houses, undated (Box N31)
    - Unidentified location--Windmills, undated (Box N31)
    - Copy negatives of other Armbruster prints, undated (Box N31)
    - Copy negatives of drawings, newspapers, undated (Box N31)
  - Subseries III, Glass Plate Negatives: 5 x 7" (and smaller)
    Subseries III generally corresponds to prints found in Series I, Subseries II. All were taken in Brooklyn in 1922. When possible, negatives have been matched to prints and titled accordingly. When no print was available, a bracketed descriptive title was assigned to each negative. Negatives are not numbered, but are ordered geographically. Within each geographic designation, negatives are arranged loosely by subject: Buildings, Churches, Houses, and Other.
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn), 1922 (Box 20)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn), 1922 (Box 21)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn), 1922 (Box 22)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Flatbush, 1922 (Box 23)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Flatbush, 1922 (Box 24)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Flatlands, 1922 (Box 24)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Flatlands, 1922 (Box 25)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Gravesend, 1922 (Box 25)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--New Utrecht, 1922 (Box 25)
  - Subseries IV, Glass Plate Negatives: 6.5 x 8.5"
    Subseries IV includes copy negatives from Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, the Brooklyn Eagle, engravings, oil paintings, pen and ink drawings; mainly of historic houses or buildings in Brooklyn. Many of these look as if Armbruster had pinned them to a board for enlarging purposes. The pins and board are visible in some of the negatives. There are also enlargements in this same manner of several of Armbruster's own prints. Copy negatives carry either Armbruster's or the original captions (and sometimes both). In cases where no caption was written on the negative, a bracketed descriptive title was assigned to each negative. Original negatives are grouped together and organized by subject. Copy negatives are also grouped together and organized by subject.
    - Original negatives: Aerial views, undated (Box 26)
    - Original negatives: Architectural Elements, undated (Box 26)
    - Original negatives: Barns, undated (Box 26)
    - Original negatives: Boats, undated (Box 26)
    - Original negatives: Churches, undated (Box 26)
    - Original negatives: Churches, undated (Box 27)
    - Original negatives: Farmhouses, undated (Box 27)
    - Original negatives: Houses, undated (Box 27)
    - Original negatives: Houses (Box 28)
    - Original negatives: Other, undated (Box 29)
    - Original negatives: People, undated (Box 29)
    - Original negatives: Rowhouses, undated (Box 29)
    - Original negatives: Street Scenes, undated (Box 29)
    - Copy Negatives: Aerial views, undated (Box 29)
    - Copy Negatives: Boats, undated (Box 29)
    - Copy Negatives: Buildings, undated (Box 29)
    - Copy Negatives: Buildings, undated (Box 30)
    - Copy Negatives: Buildings, undated (Box 31)
    - Copy Negatives: Churches, undated (Box 31)
    - Copy Negatives: Farmhouses, undated (Box 31)
    - Copy Negatives: Houses, undated (Box 32)
    - Copy Negatives: Houses, undated (Box 33)
    - Copy Negatives: Landscapes, undated (Box 33)
    - Copy Negatives: Other, undated (Box 33)
    - Copy Negatives: People, undated (Box 33)
    - Copy Negatives: Rowhouses, undated (Box 34)
    - Copy Negatives: Streets, undated (Box 34)
    - Copy Negatives: Views, undated (Box 34)
    - 2 Negative boxes with Armbruster's handwriting, undated (Box 34)
  - Subseries V, Glass Plate Negatives: 8 x 10"
    Subseries V contains mainly copy negatives. These consist of drawings of historic houses (some from newspapers or magazines.) and other views such as: Long Island Rail Road Tunnel; a map of the City of Williamsburgh; Old James Street Market, Brooklyn; View of Astoria, L.I. (printed by Currier and Ives); and Rutgers University. Original negatives show Ebbets field, the Manhattan skyline, Union Cemetary, and Armbruster's family tree. When no title was available, a bracketed descriptive title was assigned to each negative. Negatives are not numbered. Original negatives are grouped together and organized by subject. Copy negatives are also grouped together and organized by subject. Some broken negatives are in Box 35.
    - Original negatives: Aerial views, undated (Box 35)
    - Original negatives: Buildings, undated (Box 35)
    - Original negatives: Churches, undated (Box 35)
    - Original negatives: Houses, undated (Box 35)
    - Original negatives: Landscapes, undated (Box 35)
    - Original negatives: Other, undated (Box 35)
    - Original negatives: People, undated (Box 35)
    - Copy negatives: Barns, undated (Box 36)
    - Copy negatives: Buildings, undated (Box 36)
    - Copy negatives: Farmhouses, undated (Box 36)
    - Copy negatives: Houses, undated (Box 36)
    - Copy negatives: Other, undated (Box 36)
    - Copy negatives: People, undated (Box 36)
    - Copy negatives: Rowhouses, undated (Box 36)
    - Copy negatives: Views, undated (Box 36)